Someone who looks like me walks past you in the street.
يمر بك شخص ما يلبس مثلي في الشارع.
Do you think they're a mother,
هل تظن أنها أم،
a refugee
أو لاجئة
or a victim of oppression?
أو ضحية إضطهاد؟
Or do you think they're a cardiologist,
أم هل تظن إنها أخصائية قلب؟
a barrister
محامية ؟
or maybe your local politician?
أو سياسية محلية؟
Do you look me up and down,
هل تنظر لي من أعلى لأسفل ،
wondering how hot I must get
متخيلاً كيف سأكون كثيرو
or if my husband has forced me to wear this outfit?
أو إن كان زوجي أجبرني على هذا اللباس؟
What if I wore my scarf like this?
ماذا لو لبست وشاحي هكذا؟
I can walk down the street in the exact same outfit
أستطيع المشي في الشوارع بنفس الملابس
and what the world expects of me and the way I'm treated
وماذا يتوقع مني الناس وكيف يعاملونني
depends on the arrangement of this piece of cloth.
إعتمادا على ترتيب وشاحي وهو قطعة قماش.
But this isn't going to be another monologue about the hijab
هذا لن يكون حديثا آخر عن الحجاب
because Lord knows, Muslim women are so much more than the piece of cloth
لأن المسلمات لسن فقط قطعة قماش
they choose, or not, to wrap their head in.
فهن يخترن أن يربطن رأسهن أو لا يردن ذلك.
This is about looking beyond your bias.
هذا عن النظر ما وراء انحيازك.
What if I walked past you and later on
ماذا لو مررت قربك ثم بعد ذلك
you'd found out that actually I was a race car engineer,
عرفت إني مهندسة سيارات سباق،
and that I designed my own race car and I ran my university's race team,
وإنني صممت سيارة سباق شاركت بها مع فريق الجامعة،
because it's true.
لأن ذلك حقيقة.
What if I told you that I was actually trained as a boxer for five years,
ماذا لو عرفت بأني تدربت 5 سنين على الملاكمة،
because that's true, too.
وهذه أيضاً حقيقة.
Would it surprise you?
هل كان ذلك سيفاجؤك؟
Why?
لماذا ؟
Ladies and gentlemen, ultimately,
سيداتي وسادتي. في نهاية المطاف،
that surprise and the behaviors associated with it
إن هذا التفاجؤ والتصرف المرافق له
are the product of something called unconscious bias,
نتيجة شيء يسمى التحيز اللاواعي،
or implicit prejudice.
أو الانحياز الضمني،
And that results in the ridiculously detrimental
وهذا ما ينتج الضرر السخيف
lack of diversity in our workforce,
في نقص التنوع في قوانا العاملة،
particularly in areas of influence.
خاصة في مناطق النفوذ.
Hello, Australian Federal Cabinet.
أهلا وزارة أستراليا الإتحادية.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Let me just set something out from the outset:
دعوني أقول شيئا عن بداية الحديث:
Unconscious bias is not the same as conscious discrimination.
الأنحيازاللاواعي ليس مثل التفرقة الواعية.
I'm not saying that in all of you, there's a secret sexist or racist
لا أقول بأن من بينكم جميعا، متعصب للجنس متخف أو عنصري
or ageist lurking within, waiting to get out.
أو متطرف في دواخلكم ينتظر الفرصة للظهور.
That's not what I'm saying.
ليس هذا ما أقوله.
We all have our biases.
نحن جميعا لدينا انحيازات.
They're the filters through which we see the world around us.
إنها المصفاة التي من خلالها نرى العالم من حولنا.
I'm not accusing anyone,
أنا لا أتهم أحداً،
bias is not an accusation.
الانحياز ليس اتهاماً.
Rather, it's something that has to be identified,
بالعكس أنه شيء يجب تعريفه،
acknowledged and mitigated against.
و تقديره و جعله معتدلاً.
Bias can be about race,
يمكن أن يكون التحيز ضد العرق،
it can be about gender.
أو ضد الجنس.
It can also be about class, education, disability.
أو الطبقة أو الثقاففة أو الإعاقة.
The fact is, we all have biases against what's different,
الحقيقة إننا جميعا لدينا تحيز ضد ما يختلف عنا،
what's different to our social norms.
ما يختلف عن معاييرنا الاجتماعية.
The thing is, if we want to live in a world
الواقع أننا إذا أردنا الحياة في العالم
where the circumstances of your birth
حيث ظروف ولادتك
do not dictate your future
لا تقرر مستقبلك
and where equal opportunity is ubiquitous,
وحيث الفرصة متساوية ومتوفرة،
then each and every one of us has a role to play
عند ذاك يكون لكل واحد منا دوريلعبه
in making sure unconscious bias does not determine our lives.
لضمان أن لا يؤثر التحيز اللاواعي في حياتنا.
There's this really famous experiment in the space of unconscious bias
وهناك تجربة شهيرة في مجال التحيز اللاواعي
and that's in the space of gender in the 1970s and 1980s.
وذلك في مجال الجنس في السبعينات والثمانينات.
So orchestras, back in the day, were made up mostly of dudes,
حيث كانت الفرق الموسيقية عموما من الرجال،
up to only five percent were female.
ولم تزد نسبة النساء عن 5% .
And apparently, that was because men played it differently,
ويبدو أن السبب أن الرجال يعزفون بشكل مختلف،
presumably better, presumably.
بصورة أفضل فرضياً، فرضياً
But in 1952, The Boston Symphony Orchestra
ولكن في عام 1952 أوركسترا بوسطن السمفونية
started an experiment.
بدأت بتجربة.
They started blind auditions.
بدأوا بتجربة اختبارات عمياء.
So rather than face-to-face auditions, you would have to play behind a screen.
وبدلا من العزف ظاهرا فأنت تجلس وراء ستار.
Now funnily enough,
ومن الغريب تماماً،
no immediate change was registered
لم يسجل أي تغيير مباشر
until they asked the audition-ers to take their shoes off
لغاية الطلب من المشاركين نزع أحذيتهم
before they entered the room.
قبل دخولهم القاعة.
because the clickity-clack of the heels
لعدم السماح لطرقات الكعب العالي
against the hardwood floors
على الأرض الخشبية الصلبة
was enough to give the ladies away.
بفضح دخول النساء
Now get this,
والآن اسمعوا هذا
there results of the audition showed
كانت النتائج للعروض المقدمة
that there was a 50 percent increased chance
أن هناك 50% من زيادة الفرص
a woman would progress past the preliminary stage.
بأن تتقدم امرأة لتجتاز المرحلة الأولى.
And it almost tripled their chances of getting in.
و زاد هذا من احتمال قبولهن بثلاثة أضعاف.
What does that tell us?
مالذي نستنتجه من هذا؟
Well, unfortunately for the guys, men actually didn't play differently,
يعني لسوء الحظ الرجال لا يعزفون بشكل مختلف،
but there was the perception that they did.
ولكن كان هناك تصور بأنهم كذلك.
And it was that bias that was determining their outcome.
وإنه التحيز الذي شكل ذلك التصور.
So what we're doing here is identifying and acknowledging
إذا ما نفعل نحن هو تعريف و تمييز
that a bias exists.
وجود تحيز.
And look, we all do it.
نعم .نحن جميعاً نفعل ذلك.
Let me give you an example.
سأعطيكم مثلاً.
A son and his father are in a horrible car accident.
صبي وأبوه في حادث سيارة مروع.
The father dies on impact
يموت الأب بالحادث
and the son, who's severely injured, is rushed to hospital.
ويسرعون بالصبي ذي الجروح البليغة إلى المستشفى.
The surgeon looks at the son when they arrive and is like,
وينظر الجراح إلى الصبي عندما يصل ويقول،
"I can't operate."
لا أستطيع إجراء العملية
Why?
لماذا؟
"The boy is my son."
"لأن الصبي هو ابني"
How can that be?
كيف يمكن ذلك ؟
Ladies and gentlemen,
سيداتي وسادتي،
the surgeon is his mother.
الجراح هو أمه.
Now hands up -- and it's okay --
والآن لنرفع أيدينا، لا بأس
but hands up if you initially assumed the surgeon was a guy?
ارفع يدك إذا افترضت مُقدماً أن الجراح رجل؟
There's evidence that that unconscious bias exists,
هناك دليل على أن تحيز اللاوعي موجود،
but we all just have to acknowledge that it's there
وعلينا أن نُقر بوجوده
and then look at ways that we can move past it
وبعدها ننظر إلى طرق تجاوزه
so that we can look at solutions.
كي ننظر في الحلول.
around the space of unconscious bias is the topic of quotas.
حول التحيزاللاواعي هو موضوع المحاصصة.
And this something that's often brought up.
ويظهرهذا بين آن وآخر.
And of of the criticisms is this idea of merit.
واحد من الا نتقادات الموجهة لهذا هو فكرة الاستحقاق.
Look, I don't want to be picked because I'm a chick,
أنظروا، أنا لا أريد أن يتم اختياري لأنني فتاة،
I want to be picked because I have merit,
أنا أريد أنيتماختياري لأنني أستحق،
because I'm the best person for the job.
لأنني أفضل شخص لهذه الوظيفة.
It's a sentiment that's pretty common among female engineers
إنه تعبير شائع بين المهندسات الإناث
that I work with and that I know.
اللواتي أعمل معهن أو اللواتي أعرفهن.
And yeah, I get it, I've been there.
أي نعم، أعرف ذلك لأنني عايشته.
But, if the merit idea was true,
ولكن إذا كانت هذه الفكرة صحيحة،
why would identical resumes, in an experiment done in 2012 by Yale,
لماذا عندما قامت ييل عام 2012 بتجربتها،
identical resumes sent out for a lab technician,
بإرسال خلاصات خدمة متشابهة لتقني مختبر،
why would Jennifers be deemed less competent,
لماذا أُعتبرت جنيفر أقل كفاءة
be less likely to be offered the job,
وغير مناسبة لاستلام الوظيفة،
and be paid less than Johns.
ويدفع لها أقل من جونز.
The unconscious bias is there,
كان التحيز اللاواعي هناك،
but we just have to look at how we can move past it.
ولكن علينا أن نعرف كيف نتجاوزه.
And, you know, it's interesting,
وكما تعرفون، من المشوق أن نعرف
there's some research that talks about
أن هناك بعض الأبحاث تتحدث عن
why this is the case and it's called the merit paradox.
سبب هذه الحالة و تسمى مفارقة التمييز.
And in organizations -- and this is kind of ironic --
وفي أي منظمة-- كنوع من السخرية--
in organizations that talk about merit being their primary value-driver
تتحدث عن كون الاستحقاق من دوافعها الأساسية
in terms of who they hire,
بالنسبة لمن يشغلون،
they were more likely to hire dudes and more likely to pay the guys more
تشغيل الرجال ويمكن أن يدفعوا لهم أكثر
because apparently merit is a masculine quality.
لأن الظاهر إن التميز هو في الرجولة
But, hey.
ولكن اسمعوا.
So you guys think you've got a good read on me,
أيها السادة تتصورون إنكم قرأتم افكاري،
you kinda think you know what's up.
وتعتقدون إنكم تعرفون ما لذي يجري.
Can you imagine me running one of these?
هل يمكنكم تصوري وأنا أدير واحدة مثل هذه؟
Can you imagine me walking in and being like,
هل يمكن تصوري أدخل عليكم لأقول،
Well, I'm glad you can.
جيد أنا سعيدة لأنكم تستطيعون.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Because ladies and gentlemen, that's my day job.
لأنه يا سيداتي وسادتي هذا هو عملي اليومي.
And the cool thing about it is that it's pretty entertaining.
والشيء الجيد حوله هو أنه مسلي جداً.
Actually, in places like Malaysia,
و في الواقع في مناطق مثل ماليزيا،
Muslim women on rigs isn't even comment-worthy.
فإن عمل المسلمة على الآبار ليس مثيرا للاهتمام حتى.
There are that many of them.
لأنهن كثيرات هناك.
But, it is entertaining.
ولكنه أمر مسل.
I remember, I was telling one of the guys,
أتذكر إنني كنت اقول لأحد الأشخاص،
"Hey, mate, look, I really want to learn how to surf."
"يا صاح ،أنا حقا أريد تعلم ركوب الأمواج."
And he's like, "Yassmin, I don't know how you can surf
فقال،" ياسمين لا أعرف كيف ستتمكنين من ذلك
with all that gear you've got on,
بكل هذه الملابس عليك،
and I don't know any women-only beaches."
ولا أعرف سواحل خاصة للنساء."
And then, the guy came up with a brilliant idea,
ثم جاءني بفكرة ذكية،
he was like, "I know, you run that organization
وقال، "أعرف إنك تديرين تلك المنظمة
Youth Without Borders, right?
شباب بلا حدود،صحيح؟
Why don't you start a clothing line for Muslim chicks in beaches.
لم لا تبدأين موضة ملابس للمسلمات على الشواطئ.
You can call it Youth Without Boardshorts."
وتسميه شباب بلا ملابس قصيرة."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And I was like, "Thanks, guys."
فـاجبته، "شكراً لك."
I should eat all the yogurt I could
بأن على أكل كل الزبادي التي يمكنني تناولها
because that was the only culture I was going to get around there.
لأن هذه هي كل الحضارة التي أحصل عليها هنا.
But, the problem is, it's kind of true
والمشكلة هي إن هذا صحيح نوعا ما
because there's an intense lack of diversity in our workforce,
لأن هناك نقصاً شديداً في التنوع في عمالتنا،
particularly in places of influence.
خاصة في مواقع المؤثرة.
Now, in 2010,
والآن في 2010،
The Australian National University did an experiment
قامت جامعة أستراليا الوطنية بتجربة
where they sent out 4,000 identical applications
عندما أرسلوا 4000 طلبا متشابهاً
To get the same number of interviews as someone with an Anglo-Saxon name,
فكان أنه للحصول على نفس العدد من المقابلات لأسماء إنجلوسكسونية،
if you were Chinese, you had to send out 68 percent more applications.
فإن كنت صينياً فعليك إرسال 68% طلبات أكثر.
If you were Middle Eastern -- Abdel-Magied --
أما إذا كنت شرق أوسطياً --مثل عبدالمجيد--
you had to send out 64 percent,
فعليك إرسال 64%،
and if you're Italian, you're pretty lucky,
وإذا كنت إيطاليا فأنت محظوظ جدا،
you only have to send out 12 percent more.
فإن عليك أن ترسل 12% أكثر
In places like Silicon Valley, it's not that much better.
وفي أماكن مثل وادي السليكون فليس الوضع أحسن.
In Google, they put out some diversity results
ولكن في غوغل،فإنهم يقبلون بعض التنوع
all that kind of thing.
ومثل ذلك.
And the rest of the tech world is not that much better
وليس العالم التقني أفضل من ذلك بكثير
and they've acknowledged it,
وهم يعترفون بهذا
but I'm not really sure what they're doing about it.
ولكني حقا لا أعرف ماالذي يفعلونه بشأنه.
The thing is, it doesn't trickle up.
والمهم هو أن لا يزيد هذا التوجه.
In a study done by Green Park,
و في دراسة قامت بها غرين بارك،
who are a British senior exec supplier,
وهي مؤسسة بريطانية لكبار المزودين للمدراء التنفيذيين،
they said that over half of the FTSE 100 companies
نجد أن أكثر من نصف الشركات المائة الأولى
don't have a nonwhite leader at their board level,
ليس لها قيادي غير أبيض في مستوى مجالسها،
executive or non-executive.
مدراء تنفيذيين أو غير ذلك.
And two out of every three don't have an executive
وإنا ثنين من كل ثلاثة ليس لها مدير تنفيذي
who's from a minority.
من هو من الأقليات.
And most of the minorities that are at that sort of level
وإن أغلب أفراد الأقليات في ذلك المستوى
are non-executive board directors.
ليسوا من المدراء في مجالس الإدارة.
So their influence isn't that great.
لذلك فإن تأثيرهم ليس كبيراً.
I've told you a bunch of terrible things.
لقد قلت لكم بعض الأشياء الفظيعة.
You're like, "Oh my god, how bad is that? What can I do about it?"
وستقولون "يا إلهي،مامدى سوء هذا الأمر؟ ومالذي بمكتتي أن أفعل حياله؟
Well, fortunately,
حسنا ولكن لحسن الحظ،
we've identified that there's a problem.
لقد حددنا أن هنالك مشكلة.
There's a lack of opportunity, and that's due to unconscious bias.
هناك نقص في الفرص سببه التحيز اللاواعي.
But you might be sitting there thinking,
ولكنك قد تجلس وتفكر وتفول،
"I ain't brown. What's that got to do with me?"
"أنا لست أسمرا فما دخلي بهذا؟"
Let me offer you a solution.
سأعرض عليكم حلاً.
And as I've said before,
وكما قلت سابقاً،
we live in a world where we're looking for an ideal.
إننا نعيش في عالم يبحث عن نموذج مثالي.
And if we want to create a world
وإذا أردنا أن نخلق عالماً
where the circumstances of your birth don't matter,
لا تهم فيه ظروف ولادتك،
we all have to be part of the solution.
علينا أن نكون جميعاً جزء من الحل.
And interestingly, the author of the lab resume experiment
والمثير للاهتمام، أن كاتب تجربة المختبر الخاص بالسير الذاتية
offered some sort of a solution.
عرضت علينا بعض الحلول.
She said the one thing that brought the successful women together,
حيث قالت إن الشيء الوحيد الذي جمع النساء الناجحات معاً،
the one thing that they had in common,
الشيء الوحيد المشترك بينهن،
was the fact that they had good mentors.
هو حقيقة أنه كان لهن مرشدون جيدون.
So mentoring, we've all kind of heard that before,
إذن التوجيه، وكلنا سمعنا به من قبل.
it's in the vernacular.
إنه في لغتنا.
Here's another challenge for you.
وهذا تحد آخر لكم.
I challenge each and every one of you to mentor someone different.
أتحدى كل واحد منكم أن يُرشد شخصاً مختلفاً.
Think about it.
فكروا في الموضوع.
Everyone wants to mentor someone who kind of is familiar,
كل شخص يريد توجيه شخص تعوّد عليه،
who looks like us,
من يشابهنا،
we have shared experiences.
ممن لدينا معهم تجارب مشتركة.
If I see a Muslim chick who's got a bit of attitude,
لو رأيت فتاة مسلمة لها شخصية صعبة شيئا ماـ
I'm like, "What's up? We can hang out."
ساقول ،كيف الحال؟ لنتسكع قليلاً."
You walk into a room and there's someone who went to the same school,
أو تدخل غرفة و تجد شخصاً كان معك في المدرسة،
you play the same sports,
وتلعبان نفس الرياضة،
there's a high chance that you're going to want to help that person out.
هناك احتمال كبير أن ترغب بمساعدة هذا الشخص.
But for the person in the room who has no shared experiences with you
أما الشخص الذي لم يشاركك أي تجربة سابقة
it becomes extremely difficult to find that connection.
سيكون من الصعب جدا إيجاد مثل تلك الرابطة.
The idea of finding someone different to mentor,
الفكرة إيجاد شخص مختلف لتوجيهه،
someone who doesn't come from the same background as you,
شخص ليست له نفس خلفيتك.
whatever that background is,
مهما كانت خلفيتك،
is about opening doors for people who couldn't even get
إنها فتح الأبواب لأشخاص لم يتمكنوا حتى
to the damn hallway.
من الوصول حتى للمدخل اللعين.
Because ladies and gentlemen, the world is not just.
لأن العالم يا سيداتي وسادتي ليس عادلاً.
People are not born with equal opportunity.
البشر لا يولدون بفرص متساوية.
I was born in one of the poorest cities in the world, Khartoum.
أنا ولدت في إحدى المدن الفقيرة جداً في العالم،في الخرطوم.
I was born brown, I was born female,
ولدت سمراء و ولدت أنثى،
and I was born Muslim in a world that is pretty suspicious of us
وولدت مسلمة في عالم يشكك بنا،
for reasons I can't control.
لأسباب لا يمكن التحكم بها.
However, I also acknowledge the fact that I was born with privilege.
ولكني أقر بأني ولدت بامتيازات جيدة.
I was born with amazing parents,
لقد ولدت لأبوين رائعينK
I was given an education
وتم توفير التعليم لي
and had the blessing of migrating to Australia.
وتباركت بالهجرة إلى استراليا.
But also, I've been blessed with amazing mentors
كمh تباركت بالحصول على معلمين رائعين
who've opened doors for me that I didn't even know were there.
فتحوا لي أبوابا لم أكن حتى أعرف بوجودها.
A mentor who said to me,
أحد المعلمين قال لي،
"Hey, your story's interesting.
"اسمعي، إن قصتك مثيرة للاهتمام.
Let's write something about it so that I can share it with people."
دعينا نكتب عنها لنتقاسمها مع الناس."
A mentor who said,
قال أحد المعلمين،
"I know you're all those things that don't belong on an Australian rig,
"أعرف إنكم جميعا لا تنتمون إلى هذا البئر الأسترالي،
but come on anyway."
ولكن تعالوا على أي حال."
And here I am, talking to you.
وها أنا الآن أتحدث إليكم.
And I'm not the only one.
وأنا لست الوحيدة.
There's all sorts of people in my communities
هناك كل أنواع الناس في مجتمعاتي
that I see have been helped out by mentors.
الذين رأيتهم و قد ساعدهم معلمون.
A young Muslim man in Sydney
شاب مسلم في سيدني
who ended up using his mentor's help
انتهى به المطاف باستعمال مساعدة معلمه
to start up a poetry slam in Bankstown
من بدء مجموعة شعرية للصلام في بانكستاون
and now it's a huge thing.
وهي كبيرة جدا الآن.
And he's able to change the lives of so many other young people.
وأصبح قادراً على تغيير حياة الكثير من الشباب.
Or a lady here in Brisbane,
أو سيدة هنا في برسبين،
an Afghan lady who's a refugee,
سيدة أفغانية لاجئة،
who could barely speak English when she came to Australia,
كانت تتكلم الإنجليزية بصعوبة عندما قدمت إلى أستراليا،
her mentors helped her become a doctor
ساعدها معلموها أن تصبح طبيبة
and she took our Young Queenslander of the Year Award in 2008.
وحصلت على الجائزة الملكية للشباب عام 2008.
She's an inspiration.
إنها إلهام للأخرين.
This is so not smooth.
وهذا ليس سهلاً.
This is me.
هذا أنا.
But I'm also the woman in the rig clothes,
وأنا المرأة في ملابس آبار الحفر،
and I'm also the woman who was in the abaya at the beginning.
وأنا التي كنت أليس العباءة في البداية.
Would you have chosen to mentor me if you had seen me
هل كنت ستختار توجيهي لو رأيتني
in one of those other versions of who I am?
في أحد الهيئات الأخرى التي كنت بها؟
Because I'm that same person.
لأنني نفس الشخص.
We have to look past our unconscious bias,
يجب تجاوز تحيزنا اللاواعي،
find someone to mentor who's at the opposite end of your spectrum
جد شخصا لتعليمه يقف على العكس من طيفك
because structural change takes time,
لأن التغيير الهيكلي يأخذ وقتاً،
and I don't have that level of patience.
وأنا ليس لدي ذلك المستوى من الصبر.
So if we're going to create a change,
إذا أردنا إحداث ذلك التغيير،
if we're going to create a world
إذا أردنا خلق عالم
where we all have those kinds of opportunities,
حيث تكون لنا جميعا نفس هذه الفرص،
then choose to open doors for people.
إذا عليك أن تختار فتح الباب للناس.
Because you might think that diversity has nothing to do with you,
لأنك قد تعتقد أن التنوع لا علاقة له بك،
but we are all part of this system
ولكننا جميعاً جزء من هذا النظام
and we can all be part of that solution.
ويمكننا جميعا أن نكون جزءا من ذلك الحل.
And if you don't know where to find someone different,
وإن لم تتمكن من إيجاد شخص مختلف،
go to the places you wouldn't usually go.
فاذهب إلى المكان الذي لا تذهب إليه عادة.
If you enroll in private high school tutoring,
وإذا أردت التعليم في مدرسة ثانوية خاصة،
go to your local state school
اذهب الى مدرسة محلية بالولاية
or maybe just drop into your local refugee tutoring center.
أو قم بزيارة لمركز تعليم محلي للاجئين.
Or perhaps you work at an office.
أو قد تكون عاملا في مكتب.
Take out that new grad who looks totally out of place --
خذ هذا الوافد الجديد الغريب عن المكان--
'cause that was me --
لأنني كنت ذلك الشخص--
and open doors for them,
و افتح الأبواب لهم،
not in a tokenistic way, because we're not victims,
ليس بشكل رمزي لأننا لسنا ضحايا،
but show them the opportunities
ولكن أظهر لهم الفرص
because opening up your world
لأن فتح أبواب عالمك
will make you realize that you have access to doors
سيجعلك ترى أنك تستطيع الولوج لأبواب
that they didn't even know existed
لا يعرفون بوجودها أصلا
and you didn't even know they didn't have.
وأنت لم تكن تعرف إنهم لا يعرفون بها.
Ladies and gentlemen,
سيداتي وسادتي،
there is a problem in our community with lack of opportunity,
هناك مشكلة في مجتمعنا بسبب نقص الفرص،
especially due to unconscious bias.
وخاصة بسبب التحيز اللاواعي.
But each and every one one of you has the potential to change that.
ولكن لدى كل واحد منكم القدرة لتغيير ذلك.
I know you've been given a lot of challenges today,
أعرف أنكم أعطيتم الكثير من التحديات اليوم.
but if you can take this one piece and think about it a little differently,
ولكن إن أخذتم هذه المعلومة و فكرتم بها بطريقة مختلفة،
because diversity is magic.
لأن التنوع سحر.
And I encourage you to look past your initial perceptions
وأنا أشجعكم على تجاوز تصوراتكم الأولية
because I bet you,
لأنني أراهنكم،
they're probably wrong.
أنها على الأرجح خاطئة.
Thank you.
شكراً لكم.